Guide to the Andover Newton Faculty Publications Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals M-W, Series II
  - Stackhouse, Max Lynn
    - "White Candles vs. Red Flags: Religion and the Fall of the Berlin Wall." Occasional Papers On Religion In Eastern Europe. 12/5 (October 1992): 1-18 (typed manuscript) (Box 94)
    - MLS and Charles West. Globalization In Theological Education: An Evaluative Report. Pew Charitable Trust, 1993. (Box 94)
    - "Assessing an Assessment, A Response to Ronald M. Green's Review of the JOURNAL OF RELIGIOUS ETHICS." Journal of Religious Ethics. (1998): 275-279. (Box 94)
    - "The New Moral Context of Economic Life." Quarterly Review 21/3 (Fall 2001): 239-253. (Box 94)
    - You Gave the Weary Your Hand, Bearing Witness to the Light through the Shadows of September 11, 2001. (Published by the UCC-EKU Working Group.) November, 2001. (Box 94)
    - "Public Theology and Democracy's Future." Templeton Lectures on Religion and World Affairs 1996-2007. (p.26-32.), 2004 (Box 94)
    - The Will of God and the Way Things Are: Issues in the Relationship between the Contextual and the Universal Dimensions of Christian Theology., no date (Box 94)
    - "The Intellectual Crisis of a Good Idea." Journal of Religious Ethics., no date (Box 94)
  - Stearns, Oakman Sprague
    - Sartorius, Ernest. The Person and Work of Christ. Translated by OAS. Boston: Gould, Kendall, and Lincoln, 1848. (Box 95)
    - "Dr. Sears as a Theological Professor" Baptist Quarterly Review. 5:17 (1883): 57-87. (Box 95)
    - A Syllabus of the Messianic Passages in the Old Testament. Boston: Percival T. Bartless, 1884 (Box 95)
    - Introductions to the Books of the Old Testament. Boston: Silver, Burdett, 1888. (Box 95)
    - Caldwell, Samuel L. Cities of Our Faith. Biographical sketch of Dr. Caldwell by OAS. Boston: Mifflin and Company, 1890. (Box 95)
    - "Rev. Silas Stearns and Some of His Contemporaries." (A paper read before the Maine Baptist Education Society, at Bath, October 7, 1891.) (Box 95)
    - White, O.J., comp. Responsive Readings from the Old and New Testaments. Edited by OAS. Boston: Geo. H. Springer, 1896. (Box 95)
    - "The Gift of the Holy Spirit." Watchman Examiner. (February 27, 1908): 9-12. (Box 95)
  - Stuart, Moses
    - A Sermon Preached in the Tabernacle Church, Salem, Nov. 5, 1818, at the Ordination of the Rev. Messrs. Pliny Fisk, Levi Spaulding, Miron Winslow, and Henry Woodward, as Missionaries to the Unevangelized Nations. Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1818-19. [also a printing of 1819] (Box 96)
    - Letters To The Rev. Wm. E. Channing, Containing Remarks On His Sermon Recently Preached And Published At Baltimore. 2nd edition, corrected and enlarged. Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1819. (Box 96)
    - A Sermon Occasioned by the Completion of the New College Edifice for the use of the Theological Seminary at Andover, and Delivered Sept. 13, 1821. Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1821. (Box 96)
    - Jahn, Johann. Dissertations on the Importance and Best Method of Studying the Original Languages of the Bible. Translated and accompanied with notes by MS. Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1821. (Box 96)
    - Letters on the Eternal Generation of the Son of God, addressed to the Rev. Samuel Miller, DD. Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1822. (Box 96)
    - Two Discourses on the Atonement. Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1824. (Box 96)
    - A Sermon Delivered Before His Excellency Levi Lincoln, Esq., Governor ... Boston: True and Green, 1827. (Box 96)
    - Passages Cited from the Old Testament by the Writers of the New Testament Compared with the Original Hebrew and Septuagint Version Arranged by the Junior Class in the Theologial Seminary, Andover. Andover: Flagg & Gould, 1827. (Box 101)
    - A Commentary on the Epistle to the Hebrews. 2 vols. Andover: Codman Press…Flagg & Gould, 1827-28., 1827-1828 (Box 97)
    - A Brief Sketch of the Life and Character of Mrs. Elizabeth Adams. Andover: Flagg and Gould, 1829. (Box 96)
    - An Examination of the Strictures upon the American Education Society, In A Late Number Of The Biblical Repository … [Andover]: Flagg and Gould, 1829. (Box 96)
    - A Letter to William E. Channing, D.D., on the Subject of Religious Liberty. Boston: Perkins & Marvin, 1830. (Box 96)
    - A Letter to William E. Channing, D.D., on the Subject of Religious Liberty. Boston: Perkins & Marvin, 1831. 4th Edition. (Box 96)
    - A Commentary on the Epistle to the Romans, with a Translation and Various Excursus. Andover: Flagg & Gould, 1832. (Box 98)
    - A Commentary on the Epistle to the Hebrews. Andover: Flagg, Gould, and Newman, 1833. (Box 101)
    - A Commentary on the Epistle to the Hebrews Second Edition, Enlarged. Andover: Flagg, Gould and Newman, 1833. (Box 99)
    - Hints on the Interpretation of Prophecy. Andover: Allen, Morrill & Wardwell, 1842 (Box 99)
    - Hints on the Interpretation of Prophecy. 2d ed., with additions and corrections. Andover: Allen, Morrill & Wardwell, 1842. (Box 99)
    - Critical History and Defence of the Old Testament Canon. Andover: Allen, Morrill and Wardwell, 1845. (Box 99)
    - A Commentary on the Apocalypse. 2 vols. Andover: Allen, Morrill and Wardwell, 1845. (Box 100)
    - Christ a Sympathizing Saviour: a Sermon Preached at the Funeral of Mrs. Abby Woods, wife of the Rev. Leonard Woods, D.D., Andover, Mass., Feb. 24, 1846. Andover: Allen, Morrill and Wardwell, 1846. (Box 96)
    - Miscellanies, consisting of I. Letters to Dr. Channing on the Trinity; II. Two Sermons on the Atonement; III. Sacramental Sermon on the Lamb of God; IV. Dedication Sermon – Real Christianity; V. Letter to Dr. Channing on Religious Liberty; VI. Supplementary Notes and Postscripts. Andover: Allen, Morrill and Wardwell, 1846. (Box 101)
    - Letter to the Editor of the North American Review, on Hebrew Grammar. Andover: W.H. Wardwell, 1847. (Box 96)
    - Conscience and the Constitution, with Remarks on the Recent Speech of the Hon. Daniel Webster in the Senate of the United States on the Subject of Slavery. Boston: Crocker & Brewster, 1850. (Box 96)
    - A Commentary on the Book of Daniel. Boston: Crocker & Brewster, 1850. (Box 98)
    - Exegetical Essays on Several Words Relating to Future Punishment. Philadelphia: Presbyterian Publication Committee, 1867. [published posthumously] (Box 101)
  - Taylor, Sharon
    - Broken yet beloved. St. Louis: Chalice Press, 2002. (Box 103)
    - "That obnoxious dogma: future probation and the struggle to construct a Congregationalist identity." (Ph.D. dissertation, Boston College), 2004 (Box 102)
  - Taylor, John Lord
    - How Shall We Provide the Ministry that We Need? An address by JLT at his inauguration as Smith Professor in the Special Course... Andover: W.F. Draper, 1868 (Box 103)
    - A Memorial Discourse at the Last Sabbath Afternoon Service in Bartlet Chapel, Andover, October 1, 1876. Andover: W.F. Draper, 1876. (Box 103)
  - Thomas, Jesse Burgess
    - The Old Bible and the New Science. New York: Daniel C. Potter, 1877. (Box 104)
    - The Mould of Doctrine: A Study of Romans VI 17. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1883. (Box 104)
    - Both Sides: Review of Dr. Whitsitt's Question in Baptist History. Louisville, KY: Baptist Book Concern, 1897. (Box 104)
  - Thompson, J. Earl
    - "The Reform of the racist religion of the republic." The Religion of the Republic. ed. Elwyn A. Smith, 267-285. Philadelphia: Fortress Press, 1971. (Box 103)
    - "Lyman Beecher's long road to conservative abolitionism." Church History 42 (March 1973): 89-109. (Box 103)
    - (Unpublished) The Irony of Theological Education: Andover Seminary. (September 1979). (Box 103)
    - "Preventing Failure in Intimate Relationships. Disrespect, mistrust, and alienation can create a brick wall between a couple. Forgiveness can tear it down." USA Today. 124 (March 1, 1996): 40. (Draft) (Box 103)
  - Trible, Phyllis
    - God and the Rhetoric of Sexuality. Philadelphia: Fortress Press, 1978. (Box 103)
  - Valentin, Benjamin
    - Mapping public theology: beyond culture, identity, and difference. Harrisburg, PA: Trinity Press International, 2002. (Box 105)
    - New Horizons in Hispanic/Latino(a) Theology. Cleveland, OH: The Pilgrim Press, 2003. (Box 105)
    - Pinn, Anthony B., and Benjamin Valentin, eds. Creating Ourselves: African Americans and Hispanic Americans on Popular Culture and Religious Expression. Durham, NC: Duke University Press, 2009. (Box 105)
    - Valentin, Benjamin, ed. In Our Own Voices: Latino/a Renditions of Theology. Maryknoll, NY: Orbis Books, 2010. (Box 105)
    - Theological Cartographies Mapping the Encounter with God, Humanity, and Christ. Louisville, KY: Westminster John Knox Press, 2015. (Box 105)
  - Vaughan, Richard
    - Strength and Beauty, A Sermon to the King's Daughters, 1903. (Box 103)
    - Heirs of the Past, A Memorial Sermon Before the W.H. Sargent Post of the Grand Arymy of the Republic and the Woman's Relief Corps, 1904. (Box 103)
    - The Correlation of Christian Forces, October 11, 1906. Janesville: Gazette Press, 1906. (Box 103)
    - The Indwelling Christ, a Sermon preached by Richard Miner Vaughan, Professor of Christian Theology in The Newton Theological Institution to the Faculty and Students, on the Day of Prayer for Colleges, January 24, 1913. (Box 103)
    - The Holy Spirit The Helper, 1916. Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1916. (Box 103)
    - The Leadership of the Minister in Theology, 1919. (Box 103)
    - The Coinage of Life, 1923. New York City: The General Board of Promotion of the Northern Baptist Convention, 1923. (Box 103)
    - "The Christian Basis of Morality." The Rochester Theological Seminary Bulletin 77.2 (June, 1926): 77-88. (Box 103)
    - "Morality Without Religion." The Crozier Quarterly 7.3 (July, 1930): 275-293. (Box 103)
    - Address to the Graduating Class, The Ministry of Hope. June, 1935. (Box 103)
    - Evangelism and Education. Philadelphia: The American Baptist Publication Society., no date (Box 103)
    - Reasonable Religion, sermon preached in the Community Church, Babson Park, Florida by its pastor and published by members of the church, no date (Box 103)
    - Recruiting for the Ministry, Address to the Graduating Class., no date (Box 103)
  - Wan, Sze-Kar
    - Power in weakness: conflict and rhetoric in Paul's Second Letter to the Corinthians. Harrisburg, PA: Trinity Press International, 2000. (Box 103)
  - Wariboko, Nimi
    - The Depth and Destiny of Work. Trenton, NJ: Africa World Press, 2008 (Box 106)
    - God and Money: a theology of money in a globalizing world. Lanham, MD: Rowman and Littlefield, 2008. (Box 106)
    - The Principle of Excellence: A Framework for Social Ethics. Lanham, MD: Rowman and Littlefield, 2009. (Box 106)
    - Ethics and Time. Lanham, MD: Rowman and Littlefield, 2010. (Box 106)
    - The Pentecostal Principle. Grand Rapids, MI: Wm. B. Eerdmans Publishing Co., 2012. (Box 106)
    - Accounting & Money for Ministerial Leadership. Eugene, OR: Wipf & Stock, 2013 (Box 106)
    - Methods of Ethical Analysis between Theology, History, and Literature. Eugene, OR: Wipf & Stock, 2013 (Box 106)
    - Nigerian Pentecostalism. Rochester: University of Rochester Press, 2014. (Box 107)
    - The charismatic city and the public resurgence of religion. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2014. (Box 107)
    - Economics in spirit and truth. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2014. (Box 107)
  - White, Hugh Vernon
    - Truth and the Person in Christian Theology, 1963. New York: Oxford University Press, 1963. (Box 103)
  - Wilder, Amos
    - Arachne. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1928 (Box 108)
    - "Historical and Transcendental Elements in Jesus' View of the Future." Journal of Bible and Religion 5.3 (July-September, 1937): 117-119. (Box 108)
    - Personality and the Protestant Tradition. Newton Centre, MA: Andover Newton Theological School, 1940. (Box 108)
    - The Spiritual Aspects of the New Poetry. New York: Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1940. (Box 108)
    - "Voices of Our Day." Social Action 3.5 (May, 1941): 3-30. (Box 108)
    - The Healing of the Waters. New York: Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1943. (Box 108)
    - "The Sermon on the Mount Bibliography." Bulletin of the General Theological Library 37.1 (October, 1944): 5-7. (Box 108)
    - Otherworldliness and the New Testament. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1954. (Box 108)
    - New Testament Faith for Today. New York: Harper & Brothers Publishers, 1955. (Box 108)
    - "Social Factors in Early Christian Eschatology." Early Christian Origins. Chicago: Quadrangle Books, 1961: 67-76. (Box 108)
  - Wood, Nathan E.
    - Lectures in Systematic Theology as Given to the Classes in The Newton Theological Institution., no date (Box 103)
  - Woods, Leonard
    - "A Sermon Delivered at the Tabernacle in Salem, Feb. 6. 1812, on the Occasion of the Ordination of the Rev. Messrs. Samuel Newell, A.M., Adoniram Judson, A.M., Samuel Nott, A.M., Gordon Hall, A.M. and Luther Rice, A.B., Missionaries to the Heathen in Asia." Boston: Samuel T. Armstrong, 1812. (Box 109)
    - "Sermon Preached at Haverhill, (Mass.) in Remembrance of Mrs. Harriet Newell, Wife of the Rev. Samuel Newell, Missionary to India." Boston: Samuel T. Armstrong, 1815. (Box 109)
    - "Love of Popularity; A Sermon Delivered, Feb. 23, 1820, at the Installation of the Rev. Warren Fay, as Pastor of the First Congregational Church and Society in Charlestown, Mass." Charlestown: G. Clark & Co.,1820. (Box 109)
    - Letters To Unitarians And Reply To Dr. Ware. 2d Ed. Andover: Mark Newman, 1822. (Box 109)
    - "The Objection to the Inspiration of the Evangelists and Apostles from their manner of quoting texts from the Old Testament." Lecture delivered September 2, 1823 in ATS. Andover: Flagg & Gould....printers, 1824. (Box 109)
    - Knapp, Georg Chriftian. Borlefungen uber die wriftliche Glaubenslehre nad dem Lehrbegriff der evngelifchen Rirche, vol. 1-2. Halle: 1827. (Books translated into English by Woods; these volumes burned in a housefire at Woods' home) (Box 113)
    - Lectures On Infant Baptism. Andover: Mark Newman, 1829. (Box 109)
    - Lectures on the Inspiration of the Scriptures. Andover: Flagg & Gould Printers, 1829. (Box 109)
    - "Importance of a Minister's Reputation; a Sermon Delivered at the Installation of the Rev. Nathan Hewit, D.D. as Pastor of the Second Congregational Church of Christ in Bridgeport, Conn., Dec. 1, 1830." Andover: Flagg and Gould, printers, 1831. (Box 109)
    - "A Sermon on the Death of Jeremiah Evarts, Esq., Corresponding Secretary of the A.B.C.F.M. delivered in Andover July 31, 1831." Andover: Flagg and Gould, printers, 1831. (Box 109)
    - An Essay On Native Depravity. Boston: William Pierce, 1835. (Box 109)
    - WORKS. Volume I. Boston: John P. Jewett, 1851. (Box 110)
    - WORKS. Volume II-III. Boston: John P. Jewett, 1851. (Box 111)
    - WORKS. Volume IV-V. Boston: John P. Jewett, 1851. (Box 112)